
NAME
    Test-Connection
    
SYNOPSIS
    Sends ICMP echo request packets ("pings") to one or more computers.
    
SYNTAX
    Test-Connection [-ComputerName] <string[]> [[-Source] <string[]>] [-AsJob] 
    [-Authentication {Default | None | Connect | Call | Packet | PacketIntegrit
    y | PacketPrivacy | Unchanged}] [-BufferSize <int>] [-Count <int>] [-Creden
    tial <PSCredential>] [-Delay <int>] [-Impersonation {Default | Anonymous | 
    Identify | Impersonate | Delegate}] [-Quiet] [-ThrottleLimit <int>] [-TimeT
    oLive <int>] [<CommonParameters>]
    
    
DESCRIPTION
    The Test-Connection cmdlet sends Internet Control Message Protocol (ICMP) e
    cho request packets ("pings") to one or more remote computers and returns t
    he echo response replies. You can use this cmdlet to determine whether a pa
    rticular computer can be contacted across an Internet Protocol (IP) network
    . 
    
    You can use the parameters of Test-Connection to specify both the sending a
    nd receiving computers, to run the command as a background job, to set a ti
    meout and number of pings, and to configure the connection and authenticati
    on. 
    
    Unlike the traditional "ping" command, Test-Connection returns a Win32_Ping
    Status object that you can investigate in Windows PowerShell, but you can u
    se the Quiet parameter to force it to return only a Boolean value.
    

PARAMETERS
    -AsJob [<SwitchParameter>]
        Runs the command as a background job.
        
        Note: To use this parameter, the local and remote computers must be con
        figured for remoting and, on Windows Vista and later versions of Window
        s, you must open Windows PowerShell with the "Run as administrator" opt
        ion. For more information, see about_Remote_Requirements.
        
        When you use the AsJob parameter, the command immediately returns an ob
        ject that represents the background job. You can continue to work in th
        e session while the job completes. The job is created on the local comp
        uter and the results from remote computers are automatically returned t
        o the local computer. To get the job results, use the Receive-Job cmdle
        t.
        
        For more information about Windows PowerShell background jobs, see abou
        t_Jobs and about_Remote_Jobs.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                False
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -Authentication <AuthenticationLevel>
        Specifies the authentication level that is used for the  WMI connection
        . (Test-Connection uses WMI.)
        
        Valid values are:
        
        Unchanged:       The authentication level is the same as the previous c
        ommand.
        Default:         Windows Authentication.
        None:            No COM authentication.
        Connect:         Connect-level COM authentication.
        Call:            Call-level COM authentication.
        Packet:          Packet-level COM authentication.
        PacketIntegrity: Packet Integrity-level COM authentication.
        PacketPrivacy:   Packet Privacy-level COM authentication.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                4
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -BufferSize <int>
        Specifies the size, in bytes, of the buffer sent with this command. The
         default value is 32.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                32
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -ComputerName <string[]>
        Specifies the computers to ping. Type the computer names or type IP add
        resses in IPv4 or IPv6 format. Wildcard characters are not permitted. T
        his parameter is required.
        
        This parameter does not rely on Windows PowerShell remoting. You can us
        e the ComputerName parameter even if your computer is not configured to
         run remote commands.
        
        Required?                    true
        Position?                    1
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       true (ByPropertyName)
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -Count <int>
        Specifies the number of echo requests to send. The default value is 4.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                4
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -Credential <PSCredential>
        Specifies a user account that has permission to perform this action. Ty
        pe a user name, such as "User01" or "Domain01\User01", or enter a PSCre
        dential object, such as one from the Get-Credential cmdlet.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                Current user
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -Delay <int>
        Specifies the interval between pings, in seconds.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                1 (second)
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -Impersonation <ImpersonationLevel>
        Specifies the impersonation level to use when calling WMI. (Test-Connec
        tion uses WMI.) The default value is "Impersonate".
        
        Valid values are:
        
        Default:      Default impersonation.
        Anonymous:    Hides the identity of the caller.
        Identify:     Allows objects to query the credentials of the caller.
        Impersonate:  Allows objects to use the credentials of the caller.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                3
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -Quiet [<SwitchParameter>]
        Suppresses all errors and returns $True if any pings succeeded and $Fal
        se if all failed.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                False
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -Source <string[]>
        Specifies the names of the computers where the ping originates. Enter a
         comma-separated list of computer names. The default is the local compu
        ter.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    2
        Default value                Local computer
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -ThrottleLimit <int>
        Specifies the maximum number of concurrent connections that can be esta
        blished to run this command. If you omit this parameter or enter a valu
        e of 0, the default value, 32, is used.
        
        The throttle limit applies only to the current command, not to the sess
        ion or to the computer.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                32
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -TimeToLive <int>
        Specifies the maximum time, in seconds, that each echo request packet (
        "pings") is active. The default value is 80 (seconds). The alias of the
         TimeToLive parameter is TTL.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                80
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    <CommonParameters>
        This cmdlet supports the common parameters: Verbose, Debug,
        ErrorAction, ErrorVariable, WarningAction, WarningVariable,
        OutBuffer and OutVariable. For more information, type,
        "get-help about_commonparameters".
    
INPUTS
    None
        You cannot pipe input to this cmdlet.
    
    
OUTPUTS
    System.Management.ManagementObject#root\cimv2\Win32_PingStatus, System.Mana
    gement.Automation.RemotingJob, System.Boolean
        When you use the AsJob parameter, the cmdlet returns a job object. When
         you use the Quiet parameter, it returns a Boolean. Otherwise, this cmd
        let returns a Win32_PingStatus object for each ping.
    
    
NOTES
    
    
        This cmdlet uses the Win32_PingStatus class. A "get-wmiojbect win32_pin
        gstatus" command is equivalent to a Test-Connection command.
        
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 1 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>test-connection server01
    
    Source        Destination     IPV4Address     IPV6Address  Bytes    Time(ms
    )
    ------        -----------     -----------     -----------  -----    -------
    -
    ADMIN1        Server01        157.59.137.44                32       0
    ADMIN1        Server01        157.59.137.44                32       0
    ADMIN1        Server01        157.59.137.44                32       0
    ADMIN1        Server01        157.59.137.44                32       1
    
    
    Description
    -----------
    This command sends echo request packets ("pings") from the local computer t
    o the Server01 computer. This command uses the ComputerName parameter to sp
    ecify the Server01 computer, but omits the optional parameter name.
    
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 2 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>test-connection -computername server01, server02, server12 -credentia
    l domain01\user01
    
    
    Description
    -----------
    This command sends pings from the local computer to several remote computer
    s. It uses the Credential parameter to specify a user account that has perm
    ission to ping all of the remote computers.
    
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 3 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>test-connection -source Server02, Server 12, localhost -computername 
    Server01
    
    
    Description
    -----------
    This command sends pings from different source computers to a single remote
     computer, Server01. Use this command format to test the latency of connect
    ions from multiple points.
    
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 4 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>test-connection -computername Server01 -count 3 -delay 2 -TTL 256 -bu
    ffersize 256 -throttle 32
    
    
    Description
    -----------
    This command sends three pings from the local computer to the Server01 comp
    uter. It uses the parameters of Test-Connection to customize the command.
    
    Use this command format when the ping response is expected to take longer t
    han usual, either because of an extended number of hops or a high-traffic n
    etwork condition.
    
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 5 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>$job = test-connection -computername (get-content servers.txt) -asjob
    
    C:\PS> if ($job.jobstateinfo.state -ne "Running") {$results = receive-job $
    job}
    
    
    Description
    -----------
    This example shows how to run a Test-Connection command as a Windows PowerS
    hell background job. 
    
    The first command uses the Test-Connection cmdlet to ping many computers in
     an enterprise. The value of ComputerName parameter is a Get-Content comman
    d that reads a list of computer names from the Servers.txt file. The comman
    d uses the AsJob parameter to run the command as a background job.
    
    The second command checks to see that the job is not still running, and if 
    it is not, it uses a Receive-Job command to get the results and store them 
    in the $results variable.
    
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 6 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>test-connection Server55 -credential domain55\user01 -impersonation I
    dentify
    
    
    Description
    -----------
    This command uses the Test-Connection cmdlet to ping a remote computer. The
     command uses the Credential parameter to specify a user account with permi
    ssion to ping the remote computer and the Impersonation parameter to change
     the impersonation level to "Identify".
    
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 7 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>if (test-connection -computername Server01 -quiet) {new-pssession Ser
    ver01}
    
    
    Description
    -----------
    This command creates a PSSession on the Server01 only if at least one of th
    e pings sent to the computer succeeds.
    
    The command uses the Test-Connection cmdlet to ping the Server01 computer. 
    The command uses the Quiet parameter, which returns a Boolean value, instea
    d of a Win32_PingStatus object. The value is $True if any of the four pings
     succeed and is, otherwise, false.
    
    If the Test-Connection command returns a value of $True, the command uses t
    he New-PSSession cmdlet to create the PSSession.
    
    
    
    
    
    
RELATED LINKS
    Online version: http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=135266
    Add-Computer 
    Restart-Computer 
    Stop-Computer 



