
NAME
    Test-Path
    
SYNOPSIS
    Determines whether all elements of a path exist.
    
SYNTAX
    Test-Path [-LiteralPath] <string[]> [-Credential <PSCredential>] [-Exclude 
    <string[]>] [-Filter <string>] [-Include <string[]>] [-IsValid] [-PathType 
    {Any | Container | Leaf}] [-UseTransaction] [<CommonParameters>]
    
    Test-Path [-Path] <string[]> [-Credential <PSCredential>] [-Exclude <string
    []>] [-Filter <string>] [-Include <string[]>] [-IsValid] [-PathType {Any | 
    Container | Leaf}] [-UseTransaction] [<CommonParameters>]
    
    
DESCRIPTION
    The Test-Path cmdlet determines whether all elements of the path exist. It 
    returns TRUE ($true) if all elements exist and FALSE ($false) if any are mi
    ssing. It can also tell whether the path syntax is valid and whether the pa
    th leads to a container or a terminal (leaf) element.
    

PARAMETERS
    -Credential <PSCredential>
        Specifies a user account that has permission to perform this action. Th
        e default is the current user. 
        
        Type a user name, such as "User01" or "Domain01\User01". Or, enter a PS
        Credential object, such as one generated by the Get-Credential cmdlet. 
        If you type a user name, you will be prompted for a password.
        
        This parameter is not supported by any providers installed with Windows
         PowerShell.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       true (ByPropertyName)
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -Exclude <string[]>
        Omits the specified items. The value of this parameter qualifies the Pa
        th parameter. Enter a path element or pattern, such as "*.txt". Wildcar
        ds are permitted.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -Filter <string>
        Specifies a filter in the provider's format or language. The value of t
        his parameter qualifies the Path parameter. The syntax of the filter, i
        ncluding the use of wildcards, depends on the provider. Filters are mor
        e efficient than other parameters, because the provider applies them wh
        en retrieving the objects rather than having Windows PowerShell filter 
        the objects after they are retrieved.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -Include <string[]>
        Tests only the specified paths. The value of this parameter qualifies t
        he Path parameter. Enter a path element or pattern, such as "*.txt". Wi
        ldcards are permitted.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -IsValid [<SwitchParameter>]
        Determines whether the syntax of the path is correct, regardless of whe
        ther the elements of the path exist. This parameter returns TRUE if the
         path syntax is valid and FALSE if it is not.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -LiteralPath <string[]>
        Specifies a path to be tested. Unlike Path, the value of the LiteralPat
        h parameter is used exactly as it is typed. No characters are interpret
        ed as wildcards. If the path includes escape characters, enclose it in 
        single quotation marks. Single quotation marks tell Windows PowerShell 
        not to interpret any characters as escape sequences.
        
        Required?                    true
        Position?                    1
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       true (ByPropertyName)
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -Path <string[]>
        Specifies a path to be tested. Wildcards are permitted. If the path inc
        ludes spaces, enclose it in quotation marks. The parameter name ("Path"
        ) is optional.
        
        Required?                    true
        Position?                    1
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       true (ByValue, ByPropertyName)
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -PathType <TestPathType>
        Tells whether the final element in the path is of a particular type. Th
        is parameter returns TRUE if the element is of the specified type and F
        ALSE if it is not.
        
        Valid values are:
        -- Container: An element that contains other elements, such as a direct
        ory or registry key.
        
        -- Leaf: An element that does not contain other elements, such as a fil
        e.
        
        -- Any: Either a container or a leaf.Tells whether the final element in
         the path is of a particular type. Returns TRUE if the element is of th
        e specified type and FALSE if it is not.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -UseTransaction [<SwitchParameter>]
        Includes the command in the active transaction. This parameter is valid
         only when a transaction is in progress. For more information, see abou
        t_Transactions.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    <CommonParameters>
        This cmdlet supports the common parameters: Verbose, Debug,
        ErrorAction, ErrorVariable, WarningAction, WarningVariable,
        OutBuffer and OutVariable. For more information, type,
        "get-help about_commonparameters".
    
INPUTS
    System.String
        You can pipe a string that contains a path (but not a literal path) to 
        Test-Path.
    
    
OUTPUTS
    System.Boolean
        The cmdlet returns "True" when the path exists and "False" when it does
         not.
    
    
NOTES
    
    
        The cmdlets that contain the Path noun (the Path cmdlets) manipulate pa
        th names and return the names in a concise format that all Windows Powe
        rShell providers can interpret. They are designed for use in programs a
        nd scripts where you want to display all or part of a path name in a pa
        rticular format. Use them like you would use Dirname, Normpath, Realpat
        h, Join, or other path manipulators.
        
         You can use the Path cmdlets with several providers, including the Fil
        eSystem, Registry, and Certificate providers.
        
        The Test-Path cmdlet is designed to work with the data exposed by any p
        rovider. To list the providers available in your session, type "Get-PSP
        rovider". For more information, see about_Providers.
        
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 1 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>test-path -path "C:\Documents and Settings\NicoleH"
    
    
    Description
    -----------
    This command tells whether all elements in the path exist, that is, the C: 
    directory, the Documents and Settings directory, and the NicoleH directory.
     If any are missing, the cmdlet returns FALSE. Otherwise, it returns TRUE.
    
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 2 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>test-path -path $profile
    
    C:\PS>test-path -path $profile -IsValid
    
    
    Description
    -----------
    These commands test the path to the Windows PowerShell profile. 
    
    The first command determines whether all elements in the path exist. The se
    cond command determines whether the syntax of the path is correct. In this 
    case, the path is FALSE, but the syntax is correct (TRUE). These commands u
    se $profile, the automatic variable that points to the location for the pro
    file, even if the profile does not exist.
    
    For more information about automatic variables, see about_Automatic_Variabl
    es.
    
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 3 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>test-path -path "C:\CAD\Commercial Buildings\*" -exclude *.dwg
    
    
    Description
    -----------
    This command tells whether there are any files in the Commercial Buildings 
    directory other than .dwg files. 
    
    The command uses the Path parameter to specify the path. Because it include
    s a space, the path is enclosed in quotes. The asterisk at the end of the p
    ath indicates the contents of the Commercial Building directory. (With long
     paths, like this one, type the first few letters of the path, and then use
     the TAB key to complete the path.)
    
    The command uses the Exclude parameter to specify files that will be omitte
    d from the evaluation. 
    
    In this case, because the directory contains only .dwg files, the result is
     FALSE.
    
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 4 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>test-path -path $profile -pathtype leaf
    
    
    Description
    -----------
    This command tells whether the path stored in the $profile variable leads t
    o a file. In this case, because the Windows PowerShell profile is a .ps1 fi
    le, the cmdlet returns TRUE.
    
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 5 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>test-path -path HKLM:\Software\Microsoft\PowerShell\1\ShellIds\Micros
    oft.PowerShell
    
    TRUE
    
    C:\PS> test-path -path HKLM:\Software\Microsoft\PowerShell\1\ShellIds\Micro
    soft.PowerShell\ExecutionPolicy
    FALSE
    
    
    Description
    -----------
    These commands use the Test-Path cmdlet with the Windows PowerShell registr
    y provider. 
    
    The first command tests whether the registry path to the Microsoft.PowerShe
    ll registry key is correct on the system. If Windows PowerShell is installe
    d correctly, the cmdlet returns TRUE.
    
    Test-Path does not work correctly with all Windows PowerShell providers. Fo
    r example, you can use Test-Path to test the path to a registry key, but if
     you use it to test the path to a registry entry, it always returns FALSE, 
    even if the registry entry is present.
    
    
    
    
    
    
RELATED LINKS
    Online version: http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=113418
    about_Providers 
    Convert-Path 
    Split-Path 
    Resolve-Path 
    Join-Path 



