
NAME
    Get-Location
    
SYNOPSIS
    Gets information about the current working location.
    
SYNTAX
    Get-Location [-PSDrive <string[]>] [-PSProvider <string[]>] [-UseTransactio
    n] [<CommonParameters>]
    
    Get-Location [-Stack] [-StackName <string[]>] [-UseTransaction] [<CommonPar
    ameters>]
    
    
DESCRIPTION
    The Get-Location cmdlet gets an object that represents the current director
    y, much like the pwd (print working directory) command. 
    
    When you move between Windows PowerShell drives, Windows PowerShell retains
     your location in each drive. You can use Get-Location to find your locatio
    n in each drive.
    
    You can also use Get-Location to get the current directory at run time and 
    use it in functions and scripts, such as in a function that displays the cu
    rrent directory in the Windows PowerShell prompt.
    
    If you use the Push-Location cmdlet to add locations to a path stack, you c
    an use the Stack parameter of Get-Location to display the current stack.
    

PARAMETERS
    -PSDrive <string[]>
        Gets the current location in the specified Windows PowerShell drive. 
        
        For example, if you are in the Certificate: drive, you can use this par
        ameter to find your current location in the C: drive.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       true (ByPropertyName)
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -PSProvider <string[]>
        Gets the current location in the drive supported by the specified Windo
        ws PowerShell provider. 
        
        If the specified provider supports more than one drive, Get-Location re
        turns the location on the most recently accessed drive.
        
        For example, if you are in the C: drive, you can use this parameter to 
        find your current location in the drives of the Windows PowerShell Regi
        stry provider.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       true (ByPropertyName)
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -Stack [<SwitchParameter>]
        Displays the locations in the default path stack.
        
        To add paths to the default stack, use the Push-Location cmdlet.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -StackName <string[]>
        Displays the locations in the specified path stacks. 
        
        To create path stacks, use the Push-Location cmdlet.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       true (ByPropertyName)
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -UseTransaction [<SwitchParameter>]
        Includes the command in the active transaction. This parameter is valid
         only when a transaction is in progress. For more information, see abou
        t_Transactions.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    <CommonParameters>
        This cmdlet supports the common parameters: Verbose, Debug,
        ErrorAction, ErrorVariable, WarningAction, WarningVariable,
        OutBuffer and OutVariable. For more information, type,
        "get-help about_commonparameters".
    
INPUTS
    None
        You cannot pipe input to this cmdlet.
    
    
OUTPUTS
    PathInfo objects or StackInfo objects
        If you use the Stack or StackName parameters, Get-Location returns a St
        ackInfo object. Otherwise, it returns a PathInfo object.
    
    
NOTES
    
    
        Locations can be stored on a stack. The Push-Location cmdlet adds a loc
        ation to the top of the stack. The Pop-Location cmdlet gets the locatio
        n at the top of the stack.
         
        The ways that the PSProvider, PSDrive, Stack, and StackName parameters 
        interact depends on the provider. Some combinations will result in erro
        rs, such as specifying both a drive and a provider that does not expose
         that drive. If no parameters are specified, Get-Location returns the P
        athInfo object for the provider that contains the current working locat
        ion.
        
        The Get-Location cmdlet is designed to work with the data exposed by an
        y provider. To list the providers available in your session, type "Get-
        PSProvider". For more information, see about_Providers.
        
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 1 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>get-location
    
    Path
    ----
    C:\WINDOWS
    
    
    Description
    -----------
    This command displays your location in the current Windows PowerShell drive
    .
    
    For example, if you are in the Windows directory of the C: drive, it displa
    ys the path to that directory.
    
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 2 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>set-location
    
    
    Description
    -----------
    These commands demonstrate the use of Get-Location to display your current 
    location in different Windows PowerShell drives.
    
    The first command uses the Set-Location cmdlet to set the current location 
    to the Windows subdirectory of the C: drive.
    
        C:\PS> set-location C:\Windows
    
    The second command uses the Set-Location cmdlet to change the location to t
    he HKLM:\Software\Microsoft registry key. When you change to a location in 
    the HKLM: drive, Windows PowerShell retains your location in the C: drive. 
    
        PS C:\WINDOWS> set-location HKLM:\Software\Microsoft
        PS HKLM:\Software\Microsoft>
    
    The third command uses the Set-Location cmdlet to change the location to th
    e "HKCU:\Control Panel\Input Method" registry key.
    
        PS HKLM:\Software\Microsoft> set-location 'HKCU:\Control Panel\Input Me
    thod'
        PS HKCU:\Control Panel\Input Method>
    
    The fourth command uses the Get-Location cmdlet to find the current locatio
    n on the C: drive. It uses the PSDrive parameter to specify the drive.
    
        PS HKCU:\Control Panel\Input Method> get-location -psdrive c
        Path
        ----
        C:\WINDOWS
    
    The fifth command uses the Set-Location cmdlet to return to the C: drive. E
    ven though the command does not specify a subdirectory, Windows PowerShell 
    returns you to the saved location.
    
        PS HKCU:\Control Panel\Input Method> set-location C:
        PS C:\WINDOWS>
    
    The sixth command uses the Get-Location cmdlet to find the current location
     in the drives supported by the Windows PowerShell registry provider. Get-L
    ocation returns the location of the most recently accessed registry drive, 
    HKCU:.
    
        PS C:\WINDOWS> get-location -psprovider registry
        Path
        ----
        HKCU:\Control Panel\Input Method
    
    To see the current location in the HKLM: drive, you need to use the PSDrive
     parameter to specify the drive. The seventh command does just this:
    
        PS C:\WINDOWS> get-location -psdrive HKLM
        Path
        ----
        HKLM:\Software\Microsoft
    
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 3 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>set-location
    
    
    Description
    -----------
    These commands show how to use the Stack and StackName parameters of Get-Lo
    cation to list the paths in the default and alternate path stacks.
    
    The first command sets the current location to the Windows directory on the
     C: drive.
        
        C:\PS> set-location C:\Windows 
    
    The second command uses the Push-Location cmdlet to push the current locati
    on (C:\Windows) onto the path stack and change to the System32 subdirectory
    . Because no stack is specified, the current location is pushed onto the de
    fault stack.
        C:\WINDOWS>push-location System32
    
    The third command pushes the current location (C:\Windows\System32) onto th
    e Stack2 stack and changes the location to the WindowsPowerShell subirector
    y.
        
        C:\Windows\System32>push-location WindowsPowerShell -stack Stack2
    
    The fourth command uses the Get-Location cmdlet to get the paths on the def
    ault path stack.
        
        C:\WINDOWS\system32\WindowsPowerShell>get-location -stack
    
        Path
        ----
        C:\WINDOWS
    
    The last command uses the StackName parameter of Get-Location to get the pa
    ths on the Stack2 stack.
        
        C:\WINDOWS\system32\WindowsPowerShell>get-location -stackname Stack2
    
        Path
        ----
        C:\WINDOWS\system32
    
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 4 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>function prompt { 'PowerShell: ' + (get-location) + '> '}
    
    PowerShell: C:\WINDOWS>
    
    
    Description
    -----------
    This example shows how to customize the Windows PowerShell prompt. The func
    tion that defines the prompt includes a Get-Location command, which is run 
    whenever the prompt appears in the console.
    
    The format of the default Windows PowerShell prompt is defined by a special
     function called "prompt". You can change the prompt in your console by cre
    ating a new function called "prompt".
    
    To see the current prompt function, type the following command:
     
        get-content function:prompt
    
    The command begins with the "function" keyword followed by the function nam
    e, "prompt". The function body appears within braces ( {} ). 
    
    This command defines a new prompt that begins with the string "PowerShell: 
    ". To append the current location, it uses a Get-Location command, which ru
    ns when the prompt function is called. The prompt ends with the string "> "
    .
    
    
    
    
    
    
RELATED LINKS
    Online version: http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=113321
    about_Providers 
    Pop-Location 
    Push-Location 
    Set-Location 



