
NAME
    Get-Credential
    
SYNOPSIS
    Gets a credential object based on a user name and password.
    
SYNTAX
    Get-Credential [-Credential] <PSCredential> [<CommonParameters>]
    
    
DESCRIPTION
    The Get-Credential cmdlet creates a credential object for a specified user 
    name and password. You can use the credential object in security operations
    .
    
    The cmdlet prompts the user for a password or user name and password. Users
     are prompted through a dialog box or at the command line, depending on the
     system registry setting.
    

PARAMETERS
    -Credential <PSCredential>
        Specifies a user name for the credential, such as "User01" or "Domain01
        \User01". The parameter name ("Credential") is optional.
        
        When you submit the command, you will be prompted for a password. 
        
        If you enter a user name without a domain, Get-Credential inserts a bac
        kslash before the name. 
        
        If you omit this parameter, you will be prompted for a user name and a 
        password.
        
        Required?                    true
        Position?                    1
        Default value                None
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    <CommonParameters>
        This cmdlet supports the common parameters: Verbose, Debug,
        ErrorAction, ErrorVariable, WarningAction, WarningVariable,
        OutBuffer and OutVariable. For more information, type,
        "get-help about_commonparameters".
    
INPUTS
    None
        You cannot pipe input to this cmdlet.
    
    
OUTPUTS
    System.Management.Automation.PSCredential
        Get-Credential returns a credential object.
    
    
NOTES
    
    
        You can use the PSCredential object that Get-Credential creates in cmdl
        ets that request user authentication, such as those with a Credential p
        arameter.
        
        The Credential parameter is not supported by the providers that are ins
        talled with Windows PowerShell. However, you can use the Credential par
        ameter with Get-WmiObject, because it calls the Microsoft .NET Framewor
        k directly.
        
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 1 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>$c = Get-Credential
    
    
    Description
    -----------
    This command gets a credential object and saves it in the $c variable. 
    
    When you enter the command, a dialog box appears requesting a user name and
     password. When you enter the requested information, the cmdlet creates a P
    SCredential object representing the credentials of the user and saves it in
     the $c variable. 
    
    You can use the object as input to cmdlets that request user authentication
    , such as those with a Credential parameter. However, the providers that ar
    e installed with Windows PowerShell do not support the Credential parameter
    .
    
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 2 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>$c = Get-Credential
    
    C:\PS>Get-WmiObject Win32_DiskDrive -ComputerName Server01 -Credential $c
    
    
    Description
    -----------
    These commands use a credential object from Get-Credential to authenticate 
    a user on a remote computer so they can use Windows Management Instrumentat
    ion (WMI) to manage the computer.
    
    The first command gets a credential object and saves it in the $c variable.
     The second command uses the credential object in a Get-WmiObject command. 
    This command gets information about the disk drives on the Server01 compute
    r.
    
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 3 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>C:\PS>Get-WmiObject Win32_BIOS -ComputerName Server01 '
    -Credential (get-credential Domain01\User01)
    
    
    Description
    -----------
    This command shows how to include a Get-Credential command in a Get-WmiObje
    ct command.
    
    This command uses the Get-WmiObject cmdlet to get information about the BIO
    S on the Server01 computer. It uses the Credential parameter to authenticat
    e the user, Domain01\User01, and a Get-Credential command as the value of t
    he Credential parameter.
    
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 4 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>$c = Get-Credential -credential User01
    
    C:\PS>$c.Username
    
    \User01
    
    
    Description
    -----------
    This example creates a credential that includes a user name without a domai
    n name. It demonstrates that Get-Credential inserts a backslash before the 
    user name.
    
    The first command gets a credential with the user name User01 and stores it
     in the $c variable.
    
    The second command displays the value of the Username property of the resul
    ting credential object.
    
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 5 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>$credential = $host.ui.PromptForCredential("Need credentials", "Pleas
    e enter your user name and password.", "", "NetBiosUserName")
    
    
    Description
    -----------
    This command uses the PromptForCredential method to prompt the user for the
    ir user name and password. The command saves the resulting credentials in t
    he $credential variable.
    
    PromptForCredential is an alternative to using Get-Credential. When you use
     PromptForCredential, you can specify the caption, messages, and user name 
    that appear in the message box.
    
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 6 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>Set-ItemProperty 'HKLM:\SOFTWARE\Microsoft\PowerShell\1\ShellIds' Con
    solePrompting $true
    
    
    Description
    -----------
    When requiring a user name and password, as a default, a dialog box appears
     to prompt the user. To be prompted at the command line, modify the registr
    y by running this command in Windows PowerShell Run as administrator.
    
    Use the same command with "ConsolePrompting $false" to be prompted with a d
    ialog box.
    
    
    
    
    
    
RELATED LINKS
    Online version: http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=113311



