
NAME
    Get-Content
    
SYNOPSIS
    Gets the content of the item at the specified location.
    
SYNTAX
    Get-Content [-LiteralPath] <string[]> [-Credential <PSCredential>] [-Exclud
    e <string[]>] [-Filter <string>] [-Force] [-Include <string[]>] [-ReadCount
     <Int64>] [-TotalCount <Int64>] [-UseTransaction] [<CommonParameters>]
    
    Get-Content [-Path] <string[]> [-Credential <PSCredential>] [-Exclude <stri
    ng[]>] [-Filter <string>] [-Force] [-Include <string[]>] [-ReadCount <Int64
    >] [-TotalCount <Int64>] [-UseTransaction] [<CommonParameters>]
    
    
DESCRIPTION
    The Get-Content cmdlet gets the content of the item at the location specifi
    ed by the path, such as the text in a file. It reads the content one line a
    t a time and returns an object for each line.
    

PARAMETERS
    -Credential <PSCredential>
        Specifies a user account that has permission to perform this action. Th
        e default is the current user. 
        
        Type a user name, such as "User01" or "Domain01\User01", or enter a PSC
        redential object, such as one generated by the Get-Credential cmdlet. I
        f you type a user name, you will be prompted for a password.
        
        This parameter is not supported by any providers that are installed wit
        h Windows PowerShell.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       true (ByPropertyName)
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -Exclude <string[]>
        Omits the specified items. The value of this parameter qualifies the Pa
        th parameter. Enter a path element or pattern, such as "*.txt". Wildcar
        ds are permitted.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -Filter <string>
        Specifies a filter in the provider's format or language. The value of t
        his parameter qualifies the Path parameter. The syntax of the filter, i
        ncluding the use of wildcards, depends on the provider. Filters are mor
        e efficient than other parameters, because the provider applies them wh
        en retrieving the objects, rather than having Windows PowerShell filter
         the objects after they are retrieved.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -Force [<SwitchParameter>]
        Overrides restrictions that prevent the command from succeeding, just s
        o the changes do not compromise security. For example, Force will overr
        ide the read-only attribute or create directories to complete a file pa
        th, but it will not attempt to change file permissions.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -Include <string[]>
        Retrieves only the specified items. The value of this parameter qualifi
        es the Path parameter. Enter a path element or pattern, such as "*.txt"
        . Wildcards are permitted.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -LiteralPath <string[]>
        Specifies the path to an item. Unlike Path, the value of LiteralPath is
         used exactly as it is typed. No characters are interpreted as wildcard
        s. If the path includes escape characters, enclose it in single quotati
        on marks. Single quotation marks tell Windows PowerShell not to interpr
        et any characters as escape sequences.
        
        Required?                    true
        Position?                    1
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       true (ByPropertyName)
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -Path <string[]>
        Specifies the path to an item. Get-Content retrieves the content of the
         item. Wildcards are permitted. The parameter name ("Path" or "FilePath
        ") is optional.
        
        Required?                    true
        Position?                    1
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       true (ByPropertyName)
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -ReadCount <Int64>
        Specifies how many lines of content are sent through the pipeline at a 
        time. The default value is 1. A value of 0 (zero) sends all of the cont
        ent at one time. 
        
        This parameter does not change the content displayed, but it does affec
        t the time it takes to display the content. As the value of ReadCount i
        ncreases, the time it takes to return the first line increases, but the
         total time for the operation decreases. This can make a perceptible di
        fference in very large items.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       true (ByPropertyName)
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -TotalCount <Int64>
        Specifies how many lines of content are retrieved. The default is -1 (a
        ll lines).
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       true (ByPropertyName)
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -UseTransaction [<SwitchParameter>]
        Includes the command in the active transaction. This parameter is valid
         only when a transaction is in progress. For more information, see abou
        t_Transactions.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    named
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    <CommonParameters>
        This cmdlet supports the common parameters: Verbose, Debug,
        ErrorAction, ErrorVariable, WarningAction, WarningVariable,
        OutBuffer and OutVariable. For more information, type,
        "get-help about_commonparameters".
    
INPUTS
    None
        You cannot pipe input to Get-Content.
    
    
OUTPUTS
    Object
        Get-Content returns objects that represent the content that it gets. Th
        e object type depends on the content type.
    
    
NOTES
    
    
        You can also refer to Get-Content by its built-in aliases, "cat", "type
        " and "gc". For more information, see about_Aliases.
        
        The Get-Content cmdlet is designed to work with the data exposed by any
         provider. To list the providers available in your session, type "Get-P
        sProvider". For more information, see about_Providers.
        
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 1 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>get-content -Path C:\Chapters\chapter1.txt
    
    
    Description
    -----------
    This command displays the content of the Chapter1.txt file on the console. 
    It uses the Path parameter to specify the name of the item. Get-Content act
    ually passes the content down the pipeline, but because there are no other 
    pipeline elements, the content is formatted and displayed on the console.
    
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 2 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>get-content c:\Logs\Log060912.txt -totalcount 50 | set-content sample
    .txt
    
    
    Description
    -----------
    This command gets the first 50 lines of the Log060912.txt file and stores t
    hem in the sample.txt file. The command uses the Get-Content cmdlet to get 
    the text in the file. (The name of Path parameter, which is optional, is om
    itted.) The TotalCount parameter limits the retrieval to the first 50 lines
    . The pipeline operator (|) sends the result to Set-Content, which places i
    t in the sample.txt file.
    
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 3 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>(get-content cmdlets.txt -totalcount 5)[-1]
    
    
    Description
    -----------
    This command gets the fifth line of the Cmdlets.txt text file. It uses the 
    TotalCount parameter to get the first five lines and then uses array notati
    on to get the last line (indicated by "-1") of the resulting set.
    
    
    
    
    
    
RELATED LINKS
    Online version: http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=113310
    about_Providers 
    Add-Content 
    Set-Content 
    Clear-Content 



