
NAME
    Get-History
    
SYNOPSIS
    Gets a list of the commands entered during the current session.
    
SYNTAX
    Get-History [[-Id] <Int64[]>] [[-Count] <int>] [<CommonParameters>]
    
    
DESCRIPTION
    The Get-History cmdlet gets the session history, that is, the list of commands entered during the current session. 
    Windows PowerShell automatically maintains a history of each session. You can save the session history in XML or CS
    V format. By default, history files are saved in the home directory, but you can save the file in any location.
    

PARAMETERS
    -Count <int>
        Displays the specified number of the most recent history entries. The default is 32. If you use both the Count 
        and Id parameters in a command, the display ends with the command specified by the Id parameter.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    2
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       false
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    -Id <Int64[]>
        Specifies the ID number of a command in the session history. Get-History gets only the specified command. If yo
        u use Id and Count, Get-History gets the most recent commands ending with the command specified by the Id param
        eter.
        
        Required?                    false
        Position?                    1
        Default value                
        Accept pipeline input?       true (ByValue)
        Accept wildcard characters?  false
        
    <CommonParameters>
        This cmdlet supports the common parameters: Verbose, Debug,
        ErrorAction, ErrorVariable, WarningAction, WarningVariable,
        OutBuffer and OutVariable. For more information, type,
        "get-help about_commonparameters".
    
INPUTS
    Int64
        You can pipe a history ID to Get-History.
    
    
OUTPUTS
    Microsoft.PowerShell.Commands.HistoryInfo
        Get-History returns a history object for each history item that it gets.
    
    
NOTES
    
    
        The session history is a list of the commands entered during the session along with the ID. The session history
         represents the order of execution, the status, and the start and end times of the command. As you enter each c
        ommand, Windows PowerShell adds it to the history so that you can reuse it. For more information about the comm
        and history, see about_History.
        
        You can also refer to Get-History by its built-in aliases, "h", "history", and "ghy". For more information, see
         about_Aliases.
        
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 1 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>get-history
    
    
    Description
    -----------
    This command gets the 32 most recently submitted commands. The default display shows each command and its ID, which
     indicates the order of execution.
    
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 2 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>get-history | where-object {$_.commandLine -like "*service*"}
    
    
    Description
    -----------
    This command gets entries from the command history that include the word, "service". The first command gets the 32 
    most recent entries in the session history. The pipeline operator (|) passes the results to the Where-Object cmdlet
    , which selects only the commands that include "service".
    
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 3 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>get-history -id 7 -count 5 | export-csv history.csv
    
    
    Description
    -----------
    This command gets the five most recent history entries ending with entry 7. The pipeline operator (|) passes the re
    sult to the Export-Csv cmdlet, which formats the history as comma-separated text and saves it in the History.csv fi
    le. The file includes the data that is displayed when you format the history as a list, including the status and st
    art and end times of the command.
    
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 4 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>get-history -count 1
    
    
    Description
    -----------
    This command gets the last (most recently entered) command in the command history. It uses the Count parameter to d
    isplay just one command. By default, Get-History displays the most recent commands. This command can be abbreviated
     to "h -c 1" and is equivalent to pressing the up-arrow key.
    
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 5 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>get-history -count $MaximumHistoryCount
    
    
    Description
    -----------
    This command displays all of the commands saved in the session history. By default, $MaximumHistoryCount is 64, so 
    this command can be abbreviated as "h -c 64".
    
    
    
    
    
    -------------------------- EXAMPLE 6 --------------------------
    
    C:\PS>get-history | format-list
    
    
    Description
    -----------
    This command displays all of the properties of entries in the session history. The pipeline operator (|) passes the
     result to the Format-List cmdlet, which displays all of the properties of each history entry, including the ID, st
    atus, and start and end times of the command.
    
    
    
    
    
    
RELATED LINKS
    Online version: http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=113317
    about_history 
    Invoke-History 
    Add-History 
    Clear-History 



